<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: quotation | Wright Access]]></title>
  <link href="http://dpwright.github.com/blog/categories/quotation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dpwright.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-28T19:21:44+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://dpwright.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel P. Wright]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming as poetry and magic]]></title>
    <link href="http://dpwright.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/programming-as-poetry-and-magic/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T09:46:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://dpwright.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/programming-as-poetry-and-magic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from pure<br/>thought-stuff. He builds castles in the air, from air, creating by exertion of<br/>the imagination. Few media of creation are so flexible, so easy to polish and<br/>rework, so readily capable of realizing grand conceptual structures. Yet the<br/>program construct, unlike the poet's words, is real in the sense that it moves<br/>and works, producing visible outputs separate from the construct itself. It<br/>prints results, draws pictures, produces sounds, moves arms. The magic of myth<br/>and legend has come true in our time. One types the correct incantation on a<br/>keyboard, and a display screen comes to life, showing things that never were nor<br/>could be. ... The computer resembles the magic of legend in this respect, too.<br/>If one character, one pause, of the incantation is not strictly in proper<br/>form, the magic doesn't work. Human beings are not accustomed to being perfect,<br/>and few areas of human activity demand it. Adjusting to the requirement for<br/>perfection is, I think, the most difficult part of learning to program.</p><footer><strong>Frederick P. Brooks</strong> <cite>The Mythical Man-Month</cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
